so I think there are a lot of people out
there like me who like I can't do a
pistol squat to save my life but I like
uh you know I turn everything into hip
dominant movement if I go too heavy on a
squat I bend over too much and um so I
like doing exercises that work my
quads um more so than my hips and so
there's an exercise I always used to do
which I called a a step up reverse lunge
hybrid basically you you just step back
like that and kind of sink down like
that and come up but this is still this
is still a very hip dominant move what I
found was if I kind of turn this leg to
the side stayed real upright and tried
to keep most of the tension on this
leg then I could kind of turn this it's
almost like a Single Leg pistol squat so
I'll show you but I I'm just going to
I'm just going to come down like this
and I sink down and I put the weight
onto this leg staying upright I just use
this leg just enough to provide
assistance to to push myself up so it's
kind of like a a little bit like a
pistol so so I just do 10 of these I'll
show you what it looks like um so I come
down sink down into this leg just give
enough assistance here come up
just like that anyway after after I get
10 of them my my quads are just smoked
so this is a very knee dominant way to
do a a single leg exercise and make it
really knee dominant um it's still a
good hip exercise but this is a good way
to progress towards doing pistol squats
as well
[Music]